In this video, I will introduce you to the key needle animation function.
In 2025.0, the key needle can be applied to various elements, such as colors, fabrics, panels, joints, fixed needles, and wind control devices,
to achieve natural transition animation at any time.
The original animation mode was changed to animation editor after this update,
which is convenient for everyone to make animation directly in the simulation mode.
The overall usability has also been improved.
Click on the animation in the top menu, then select the animation editor to open it.
First, let's take a look at the animation editor layout after the update, and see how to set up the key needle.
You can see that the tool bar at the top of the editor retains familiar options,
such as recording, playback, camera animation, and simulation quality.
In addition, the automatic key needle function has been added,
and other settings related to the configuration have been moved to the configuration panel on the right.
On the left side of the editor,
the animation layer list will be set to the tree structure,
and the animation object in the scene will be displayed.
When applying animation, the costume, wind controller, and flag will appear as the object layer in the top layer.
Click on the triangle next to each object to check the properties that can be animated.
These properties will be displayed as the property layer.
The name of the object layer cannot be edited directly in the animation editor,
but for some objects, you can rename them in the object window scene selection card.
To set up the key needle,
please click on the right side of the property layer to insert the key needle.
According to the different properties,
you can use the option box to start or stop using the property,
or enter the specific value to manually set up the key needle.
The key needle will be displayed as a zero-shape icon,
easy to identify.
The animation track in the middle of the screen will be adjusted to display the animation range of each object,
helping you to clearly control the animation time and space.
Animated animation based on simulation storage,
such as costume or software model animation,
will be displayed as red,
while key needle animation will be displayed as gray.
Click on the animation button on the top left side
to open a list of objects that support animation,
including colors,
materials,
panels,
virtual models,
and cameras.
After selecting the object,
it will be added to the list of objects,
and you can apply the key needle for it.
Next,
let's take a look at the time line area in the middle of the interface.
The curve line above the gray bar on the top of the top part
indicates the range of play.
It defines the part that will be played in the animation.
You can adjust the range of play in the following ways.
Drag both ends,
directly drag the two ends of the gray bar,
drag the entire time axis,
press the mouse button to drag the entire gray bar,
and you can move the play range.
The key needle and end needle after adjustment
will also be implemented in the configuration panel.
You can also directly enter values ​​in the configuration panel
to set them.
Click on the right arrow on the time axis,
you can choose to set the starting or ending needle,
and set the current needle as the starting or end point of the play range.
Choose to limit the range in the action needle,
the play range will automatically adjust to the position of all existing key needles.
In addition,
you can press the Ctrl key and roll the mouse wheel to search for the size of the time axis,
so that you can check the range of the needle more carefully.
The time axis slider at the bottom allows you to set the range of the needle.
Click on the right arrow in the slider area,
there will be three options.
Choose to configure the action needle,
the time axis will automatically adjust to all animation layers,
and the range between the first and last key needle in the animation layer.
To configure the play range,
adjust the test picture according to the currently defined play range.
To configure all needles,
adjust the test picture according to the current time axis
with the smallest and largest needles set at both ends of the slider.
You can also directly click on the button on the right side of the input frame of the end needle to complete this operation.
The configuration panel on the right allows you to control some general play settings,
such as the time axis range,
scene time curve and display units.
Two new options have been added,
the real time and save time.
The real time,
which is often referred to as FPS,
it defines the rate of play per second.
The higher the real time,
the smoother the animation playback,
but it will also increase the rendering time and file size.
You can choose the right real time according to the needs of the project,
to balance quality and performance.
Save time,
control how to deal with the key needle when changing the real time.
When this option is closed,
the total play time will remain unchanged,
but the real time of the key needle will be adjusted according to the new real time per second.
When this option is turned on,
the real time of the key needle will remain unchanged,
and the total play time will be adjusted according to the new real time per second.
Through these new functions,
you can more flexibly control the range and speed of animation playback,
and optimize your workflow.
Now let's learn how to create and edit animation.
For save animation based on simulation,
such as clothing or software models,
you can continue to use the record button as before.
In the 2025 version,
we added the function of cutting and merging animation layers.
In the past,
we often needed to go through the third-party software
to edit and record the good animation layers.
Now,
you can freely cut or merge them according to your needs.
To cut a layer,
right-click on the layer you want to cut,
then select the cut layer.
The layer will be cut in the current real time,
and the chip will appear directly in the track above the original layer.
To merge multiple layers,
press the Ctrl key,
and select the layer you want to merge.
Or use the Shift key to select continuously,
then right-click and select the merge layer.
When merging layers,
it will be the top layer as the standard.
Because the current animation layer is cut and received,
so the effect between them is naturally continued.
If there is a overlap,
the higher-level data will be prioritized during the merging process.
We can also play and check the effect before merging the layer.
This is consistent with the effect after merging.
After confirming the effect,
merge layer operation is possible.
In the case of file storage animation,
it is different from the object listed in the animation menu.
It requires manual setting of keyframes,
so that the animation works.
Let's look at every animation project,
and review how to set keyframes,
and other important things to note.
We will start from the color animation.
There are two ways to set keyframes,
use the add animation button in the layer table.
Set directly from the editor
or attribute editor of the object.
Click on the add animation button.
Select the color.
Create an empty flag layer, then click on the triangle on the left
Open layer, check its properties
In the drop-down menu, you can see the flag list that can be used for clothing
The content of the flag list display will be updated in real time according to the flag in the flag editor
Now, we first add a key pin for the white flag
The first key pin will appear on the first pin in the hidden layer
The key pin is based on the setting of the current pin
You can directly move the head to the target pin
Then select the flag color and click to insert the key pin
Or enter the number of pins in the current pin input frame
It's the same, select the flag color and click to insert the key pin
To check whether the key pin has been added correctly
You can use the arrow buttons on the left and right sides of the key pin
They can make you quickly jump between the existing key pins
After confirming that the key pin is in place, return to the first pin and click the play button
You will see the flag color smooth
The natural animation effect is presented by the set key pin
Now let's see how to add the key pin directly from the flag editor
Move to the position you want to add the key pin
Select a flag color and then click to insert the key pin in the upper right corner of the editor
After adding the key pin, you can drag the two ends of the object layer to adjust the overall length
At the same time, keep the relative distance between them
You can also drag the entire layer to move all key pins at once
Or press and drag each key pin to a new position to adjust its position
You can select multiple key pins together by clicking or pressing Shift
And as a group of movements, keep them relative
To delete a specific key pin, please press and drag each key pin to select multiple key pins
Then right-click and select Delete Key Pin
Or press the Delete key on the keyboard to delete the key pin
If the animation layer is too much to slow down the playback
You can click the eye icon on the left side
Activate or turn off the playback of one animation
Let's just play it and see the current speed
Now cut back to the first pin
Turn off the animation of the flag color
You can see that after turning off the flag color animation layer
The playback speed of the animation is obviously faster
If you want to delete the animation layer
Please right-click on the layer in the list
Then select Delete Layer
Since the layer uses a tree structure
Therefore, deleting the object layer will also delete the related attribute layer
If you accidentally delete the attribute layer
You can right-click on the object layer and select
Increase layer to re-add
You will see a list of movable attributes
And you can choose the attribute to be added separately
Now let's see how to create a virtual model animation
Including using the joint point to adjust the posture and set the key pin
Click the Increase Animation button
The mouse will stop on the virtual model list
At this time, the virtual model list added in the current scene will appear
Click the virtual model you need
Add it to the layer list
Click the triangle to open and check its attribute layer
To add the current position as the first key pin
Please set the current pin as 0 first
Then click the key pin button on the right side to set the key pin
Press the Shift and X keys on the keyboard
You can display the virtual model's joint point in the 3D window
Next, move the playback head to change the position of the pin
Adjust the joint point to modify the posture
Then click the key pin button on the right side of the joint layer to insert the key pin button
Set another key pin
Because virtual model animation usually needs to be repeated
The steps of moving the pin, adjusting the position and inserting the key pin
Therefore, the automatic key pin function will be more efficient
You can insert the key pin manually in the first pin
Open the automatic key pin
In this way, any subsequent joint adjustment will automatically generate the key pin
If the pin already has a key pin
The new position will cover the existing key pin
Now the virtual model's posture is roughly edited
Let's cut back to the first pin first
To confirm the animation effect
After confirming the current effect
You can also copy and paste the key pin
Click or drag to select one or more key pins
Right-click and select Copy Key Pin
Or press Ctrl and C on the keyboard
Move the playback head to the pin to be pasted
Then right-click and select Paste Key Pin
Or press Ctrl and V
The key pin will be pasted on the current pin
If you paste multiple key pins
It will also keep the original pin
Now let's play it again
Check the animation effect after pasting the key pin
You can also right-click on the object layer
And use it in the right-click menu
Adjust the joint pin and move to the ground function
In addition, you can also download and modify the existing MTN file
But in order to avoid remodeling in the current scene
Please open the file in the new window
Now let's see how to set the animation for the board
By adding a key pin
You can control the change of the material on the selected board at any time
To create animation
After selecting the board
You can increase the animation by pressing the animation button
But for the board
It is usually more efficient to insert the key pin directly from the property editor
First, the position where the key pin needs to be added is set
This place has been set as the hand pin
Then select the board with the animation effect to be increased
In the property editor
Select the material for the board to be used
Then click the key pin next to the material
This will automatically add the board to the layer table
And insert a fabric key pin in the current pin
Then move the playhead to another pin
At this time, you can also click to open the automatic key pin
Reduce the operation
Change the fabric in the property editor
You can repeat this process according to your needs
When playing animation
You will see that the fabric of the selected board changes with time
Now let's see how to set the animation for the fabric property
You can set the key pin for the fabric property and the physical property separately
Click the increase animation button
Then select the fabric to be set for animation
The selected fabric will be added to the layer table as the object layer
Click the triangle to open it
You can see the property layer automatically listed below
These property layers include some PBR properties and physical properties
If the front side of the fabric and the back side use different textures
You can set the key pin for each surface property separately
If you only want to add a specific property to the layer table
You can select the fabric in the object window
Then you can set the key pin according to the usual way
Set the current pin, adjust the value
Then click to insert the key pin
Because the automatic key pin is opened here
So next you just need to modify the corresponding property parameters
You can add the key pin to the current pin
But please remember that the pattern, fabric and color animation
All control properties related to the fabric
If you change these three types of animation
They are applied to the same piece of clothing
Their interaction may lead to unexpected results
Therefore, it is recommended to separate the pattern or fabric animation from the color animation
Next, let's see how to set the animation of the simulation property
Click the increase animation button
Then select the simulation property
An object layer will be added to the layer table
But it will not display any property layer in the default situation
To display the property layer
You need to right-click and select the simulation property in the 3D window
Or click on the simulation property layer in the list
The preview will be changed to self-defined
Then you can set the key pin of gravity and air resistance
Next, I will introduce how to set the fixed pin animation
Fixed pin animation allows you to set the key pin in the activation or loss state of the fixed pin
First, you need to add a fixed pin in the 3D window
Then use the increase animation button to add the fixed pin object to the layer table
It should be noted that the default name of the fixed pin and the wind controller when creating is the same
Therefore, it is recommended that you add a fixed pin
Select and rename it in the property editor
In this way, you can quickly select the fixed pin that needs to be edited
To control the transition between key pins and adjust the animation speed
You can set the transition effect
To change the transition effect
Please select the key pin you need
Right-click on the key pin
Then select the transition effect from the menu
The long-term transition effect will maintain the current transition effect unchanged
Until the next key pin is switched to the corresponding effect
To make immediate changes
The linear transition effect uses the function of connecting different key pins with a straight line
To make a smooth and stable transition
The three-time transition effect uses the function of connecting the key pins with a curved line
To achieve a more dynamic transition effect
When using three or more key pins, this function is especially effective
Because the transition looks more natural
According to the attribute type selected by the key pin in the layer
The transition effect that only uses support in the menu
To change the transition effect of the key pin
The same type will be automatically applied to all key pins in the same position below
Finally, click the cancel stop button
You can separate the animation editor window into an independent window
After canceling the stop, you can click full screen
The editor expands to full screen
In dual display settings
You can use the editor on a separate screen
To improve the workflow
To restore the original window size
Please click the restore button
To restart the editor to the colou interface
Please click the stop button
Then the content about the key pin animation is introduced here
Because the wind controller and the camera animation follow the same workflow
There is no need to introduce too much
If you want to know more detailed information, please visit the user manual
I hope you can use your imagination
Through the new function of the animation editor
To create dynamic and wonderful content
Thank you for watching